A Guide to the Papers of Sir Fitzroy Maclean 1827-1966
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Series II
  - Miscellaneous Literary Material
    - Articles 1993 (Box 65)
      re Canary Islands
    - Articles 1993-1994 (Box 65)
      re Oman
    - Articles 1994-1995 (Box 65)
      re Tibet--Correspondence, Travel Arrangements, and Memorabilia
    - Articles 1995 May-Dec, 2 folders (Box 66)
      re Tibet
    - Article: "Return Journey" 1995 (Box 66)
      re the Channel Tunnel
    - Article: "So Farewell, Mr. Bond... He Was Aware of a Strange Flavor" 1996 (Box 66)
    - Article: "Britain Still Needs Stuffed Shirts and Cookie Pushers" 1996 (Box 66)
    - Articles ca. 1935-1996, 11 folders (Box 66)
      re Fitzroy Maclean, some in German, French, Serbo-Croatian, Swedish, and Dutch
    - Book Reviews, including The Life of Ian Fleming by Donald McCormick 1949-1994, 4 folders (Box 67)
    - Chapter "Captain Waugh" for The World of Evelyn Waugh 1972-1973 (Box 67)
    - Chapter for The Queen Mother Remembered1992, 1994 (Box 67)
    - Commonplace Books n.d., 3 notebooks (Box 67)
    - Contribution to Festschrift for Hans ("Johnnie") von Herwarth: Correspondence 1973-1974 (Box 67)
    - Impressions of Field Marshal Lord Wilson ("Jumbo") for Biography by David Chandler 1979-1980 (Box 67)
    - Introductions to Other Author's Books 1963-1990 (Box 67)
    - Introduction to Hans ("Johnnie") von Herwarth's Against Two Evils 1979-1980 (Box 67)
    - Lectures & Speeches: Miscellaneous Topics 1950-1970 (Box 67)
    - Lectures & Speeches: "Escape to Adventure" 1951 & 1961 (Box 67)
    - Lectures & Speeches 1972-1989 (Box 67)
    - Lectures & Speeches: Winston Churchill Centenary Dinner 1974 (Box 67)
    - Lectures & Speeches: Winston Churchill Tribute at the Music Therapy Concert at Blenheim Palace 1977-1978 (Box 67)
    - Lectures & Speeches: "By Land from Gilgit to Hong Kong" 1989 Jan 5 (Box 67)
    - Lectures & Speeches: Speech on Receiving the Brown Bear Award, Brown University 1995 (Box 67)
    - Lectures & Speeches 1995 (Box 67)
    - Lectures & Speeches n.d. (Box 68)
    - Literary Correspondence 1975-1976 (Box 68)
      re Publication of Evelyn Waugh's Diaries, which include references to Fitzroy Maclean
    - Literary Correspondence with Curtis Brown, Aitken and Stone, and Others 1973-1994 (Box 68)
    - Literary Correspondence with A.D. Peters Literary Agency 1979-1987 (Box 68)
    - Literary Correspondences with Little, Brown 1976-1982 (Box 68)
    - Literary Correspondence with Weidenfeld and Nicolson 1978-1988 (Box 68)
    - Literary Correspondence with Jonathan Cape 1980-1989 (Box 68)
    - Literary Correspondence with Joachim Spencker 1982 (Box 68)
      re Invitation to Frankfurt
    - Literary Correspondence 1982-1984, 2 folders (Box 68)
      re German Translations of Isles of the Sea and Eastern Approaches
    - Literary Correspondence with Bato Tomasevic of Motovon Group (Yugoslav Publisher) 1984-1986 (Box 68)
    - Literary Correspondence with Mainstream Publishing 1992 (Box 68)
      re Proposed Book of Interviews including Fitzroy Maclean
    - Notes for article on Hungary n.d. (Box 68)
    - Obiturary Addresses & Notices by Fitzroy Maclean ca. 1964-1995, 19 folders (Box 68)
      some accompanied by correspondence, including: Violet Asquith, Nancy Astor, Charles Bohlen, John Bute, Nicolae Causescu, Earl Cawdor, Thomas Churchill, John Clarke, the Queen Mother, Lord Lovat, Charles Maclean, Andrew Maxwell, Paddy Mayne and Bill Elliot, Iain Moncrieffe, Peter Moore, David Scott, David Stirling, and Lord Ward
    - Obiturary Addresses & Notices by Others 1984-1988, n.d. (Box 68)
    - Radio Transcripts of BBC Broadcasts including "The Week in Parliament," "Japan," "China," and "Korea" 1946-1947 (Box 68)
    - Radio Transcripts of BBC Broadcasts including "The International Scene as I See It" and "Escape to Adventure" 1948-1950 (Box 68)
    - Radio Transcripts of BBC Broadcasts on Turkey, Persia, Britain's Defense Policy, the Hydrogen Bomb, and Others 1953-1963 (Box 69)
    - Radio Transcripts of BBC Broadcasts "English in Politics" 1964 (Box 69)
    - Radio Transcripts of BBC Broadcasts "Mongolia and its Giant Neighbor" 1965 (Box 69)
    - Radio Transcripts of BBC Broadcasts "Churchill Man of Action" 1965-1966 (Box 69)
    - Radio Transcripts of BBC Broadcasts "With Great Pleasure" 1978-1979 (Box 69)
    - Radio Transcripts of BBC Broadcasts Series "Home Truths" 1993-1994 (Box 69)
    - Radio & Television: Miscellaneous Programs 1991-1996 (Box 69)
    - Royalty Statements 1977-1995, 3 folders (Box 69)
    - Television: Miscellaneous Programs 1960-1989, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Television: Transcripts of BBC Broadcast "Mongolia" 1963-1964 (Box 69)
    - Television: NATO Parliamentarians Conference Coverage-- Correspondence 1964 (Box 69)
    - Television: "This is Your Life" 1984-1985 (Box 69)
- Photographic Material
  - Photograph Albums--Armenia 1961, 1975, n.d., 3 volumes (Box 70)
  - Photograph Albums--Bakhara, formerly Uzbek, presently Uzbekistan n.d. (Box 70)
  - Photograph Albums--Caucasus 1967, 1972-1974, n.d., 3 volumes (Box 70)
  - Photograph Albums--Caucasus 1967-1974, 5 volumes (Box 71)
  - Photograph Albums--Caucasus & Georgia n.d. (Box 71)
  - Photograph Albums--Central Asia 1965-1967, 2 volumes (Box 72)
    People
  - Photograph Albums--Georgia 1961, 1967, n.d., 4 volumes (Box 72)
  - Photograph Albums--"Journey Into History" n.d., 3 volumes (Box 72)
  - Photograph Albums--Leningrad, Russia 1965 & 1967, 2 volumes (Box 73)
  - Photograph Albums--Moscow, Russia 1961-1967, n.d., 6 volumes (Box 73)
  - Photograph Albums--Moscow & Leningrad, Russia 1965-1967 (Box 74)
  - Photograph Albums--Khiva, Uzbekistan & Kazakhstan 1967 (Box 74)
  - Photograph Albums--Samarkand, Uzbekistan 1965-1967 (Box 74)
  - Photograph Albums--Yugoslavian Army, Tito, Zagreb 1953 Sep 26 (Box 74)
  - Photograph Contacts & Negatives, including Afghanistan 1938-1964, 10 folders (Box 75)
  - Photograph Contacts & Negatives 1965-1967, 1970-1974, 7 folders (Box 76)
  - Photograph Contacts & Negatives 1974-1986, n.d., 11 folders (Box 77)
  - Photographs-- Back to Bokhara Illustrations 1958 (Box 78)
  - Photographs--The Balkans 1952, 3 folders (Box 78)
  - Photographs--Caucasus Area 1958-1981, n.d. (Box 78)
  - Photographs--Central Asia 1958, n.d., 2 folders (Box 78)
  - Photographs--Central Asia (Miscellaneous), including Afghanistan ca. 1939-1967 (Box 78)
  - Photographs-- Disputed Barricade Illustrations 1957 (Box 78)
  - Photographs-- Eastern Approaches Illustrations ca. 1949 (Box 78)
  - Photographs-- Eastern Approaches Illustrations ca. 1949 (Oversize H.S. 16)
  - Photographs--Friends of Fitzroy Maclean n.d. (Box 78)
  - Photographs--Georgia ca. 1965-1967 (Box 79)
  - Photographs--Georgian Military Highway ca. 1967-1974, n.d. (Box 79)
  - Photographs--Kazakhstan--Alma Ata 1967 (Box 79)
  - Photographs--Fitzroy Maclean, Winston Churchill, Margaret Thatcher, Tito, etc. ca. 1959-1993, n.d. (Box 79)
  - Photographs--Mongolia 1987, n.d. (Box 79)
  - Photographs--Persia (Iran) & Turkey 1952-1953 (Box 79)
  - Photographs-- A Person From England Illustrations 1958, 2 folders (Box 79)
  - Photographs-- A Person from England Illustrations ca. 1958 (Oversize H.S. 16)
  - Photographs-- Portrait of the Soviet Union Illustrations ca. 1958-1988 (Box 80)
  - Photographs--Russia 1958-1987, n.d., 2 folders (Box 80)
  - Photographs--Soviet Union n.d. (Box 80)
  - Photographs--Tajikistan 1965 (Box 80)
  - Photographs--Uzbekistan--Bokhara 1958, 1967, 2 folders (Box 80)
  - Photographs--Uzbekistan--Bokhara 1967, n.d., 2 folders (Box 81)
  - Photographs--Uzbekistan--Bokhara & Khiva 1986, n.d. (Box 81)
  - Photographs--Uzbekistan--Khiva 1967 (Box 81)
  - Photographs--Uzbekistan--Samarkand 1958, 1965, 1967, 3 folders (Box 81)
  - Photographs--Uzbekistan--Samarkand & Urgut 1958 & 1967 (Box 81)
  - Photographs--Uzbekistan--Tashkent 1965 & 1967 (Box 81)
  - Photographs--Yugoslavia ca. 1941-1970 (Box 81)
  - Photographs--Yugoslavia/ Dalmatia 1952-1953 (Box 81)
  - Slides--Armenia 1974-1975, 1986, 3 folders (Box 82)
  - Slides--Baltic States 1986, 3 folders (Box 82)
  - Slides--Baltic States 1986 (Box 83)
  - Slides--Caucasus Mountain Region ca. 1985-1987, n.d., 4 folders (Box 83)
  - Slides--Central Asia 1986-1987, 5 folders (Box 84)
  - Slides--Georgia, President of n.d. (Box 84)
  - Slides--Kazakhstan--Alma Ata 1967 (Box 84)
  - Slides--Kirghizia 1986 Oct (Box 85)
  - Slides--Mongolia 1963, 1986, 2 folders (Box 85)
  - Slides--Russia--Leningrad (St. Petersburg) 1986 (Box 85)
  - Slides--Russia--Miscellaneous 1986, n.d. (Box 85)
  - Slides--Russia--Moscow 1965-1975 (Box 85)
  - Slides--Russia--Moscow 1965-1976, 1985-1986, 5 folders (Box 86)
  - Slides--Russia--Moscow 1986 (Box 87)
  - Slides--Russia--Moscow 1965-1976, 2 folders (Box 87)
    Environs & Monasteries
  - Slides--Russia--Moscow n.d. (Box 87)
    GUM Store, Race Track, & Fashions
  - Slides--Russia--Moscow 1986 (Box 87)
    The Kremlin & Red Square
  - Slides--Russia--Novosibirsk n.d. (Box 87)
  - Slides--Russia--Ordzhonikidze 1965-1972, n.d., 2 folders (Box 88)
  - Slides--Russia--Ordzhonikidze, Fiagdon, Caucasus Mountains, and Mamison Pass 1972-1974, n.d., 3 folders (Box 88)
  - Slides--Russia--Pereslavl n.d. (Box 89)
  - Slides--Russia--Pskov 1976, n.d., 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Slides--Russia--Pyatigorsk and Elburz 1972 (Box 89)
  - Slides--Russia--Zagorsk 1974-1976 (Box 89)
  - Slides--Tajikistan--Pendzhikent and Uzbekistan--Samarkand 1958-1967, 3 folders (Box 90)
  - Slides--Turkmenistan--Merv n.d. (Box 89)
  - Slides--Turkmenistan, Tajikistan, Kazakhstan, and Uzbekistan n.d. (Box 90)
  - Slides--Turkmenistan, Tajikistan, Kazakhstan, and Uzbekistan n.d. (Box 91)
  - Slides--Uzbekistan 1986 (Box 91)
  - Slides--Uzbekistan--Bokhara, Samarkand, etc. 1986 Oct, 2 folders (Box 91)
  - Slides--Uzbekistan--Bokhara & Khiva n.d. (Box 91)
  - Slides--Uzbekistan--Bokhara, Samarkand 1983 & 1986 (Box 92)
  - Slides--Uzbekistan--Fergana & Kokand and Kirghizia 1986 Oct (Box 92)
  - Slides--Uzbekistan--Fergana n.d., 3 folders (Box 92)
  - Slides--Uzbekistan--Kokand & Fergana n.d. (Box 93)
  - Slides--Uzbekistan--Samarkand 1986 Oct (Box 93)
  - Slides--Volga River Towns, Zagorsk, Pskov, Novgorod, & Vladimir 1986 (Box 93)
  - Slides--Volga Town 1987 (Box 93)